now we have Hyung Won give a talk. So he's
currently a research scientist at on the OpenAI
ChatGPT team. He has worked on various aspects of
large language models. Things like pre-training,
instruction fine tuning, reinforcement learning
with human feedback, reasoning, and so forth.
And some of his notable works include the scaling
flan papers such as FLAN-T5, as well as Flan-PALM,
and T5X, the training framework used to train
the PALM language model. And before OpenAI,
he was at Google Brain, and he received his
PhD from MIT. So give a hand for Hyung Won.
Do we switch the slides?
All right. My name
is Hyung Won, and I'm really happy to be here
today. And this week I was thinking about--
by the way, is mic working fine? Yeah. So this
week I thought about-- OK, I'm giving a lecture
on transformers at Stanford. What should I
talk about? And I thought, OK, some of you in
this room and in Zoom will actually go shape the
future of AI, so maybe I should talk about that.
It's a really important goal and ambitious, and
we really have to get it right. So that could
be a good topic to think about. And when
we talk about something into the future,
the best place to get an advice is to
look into the history. And in particular,
we'll look at the early history of transformer,
and try to learn many lessons from there.
And the goal will be to develop a unified
perspective in which we can look into many
seemingly disjoint events. And from
that we can probably hope to project
into the future what might be coming. And
so that will be the goal of this lecture,
and we'll look at some of the architectures
of the transformers, so let's get started.
Everyone I see is saying, AI is so advancing so
fast that it's so hard to keep up. And it doesn't
matter if you have years of experience, there
are so many things are coming out every week
that it's just hard to keep up. And I do see
many people spend a lot of time and energy
catching up with this latest developments, the
cutting edge and the newest thing, and then not
enough attention goes into old things because
they become deprecated and no longer relevant.
But I think it's important, actually, to look into
that because we really need to-- when things are
moving so fast beyond our ability to catch up
what we need to do is study the change itself.
And that means we can look back at the previous
things, and then look at the current thing,
and try to map how we got here, and from which we
can look into what where we are heading towards.
So what does it mean to study the change itself?
First, we need to identify the dominant driving
forces behind the change. So here dominant
is an important word because typically,
a change has many, many driving forces, and we
only care about the dominant one because we're
not trying to get really accurate, we just
want to have the sense of directionality.
Second, we need to understand the driving force
really well, and then after that we can predict
the future trajectory by rolling out the driving
force and so on. And you heard that right,
I mentioned about predicting the future, this is
a computer science class not like an astrology or
something. But we do-- I think it's actually
not that impossible to predict some future
trajectory of a very narrow scientific domain.
And that endeavor is really useful to do because
let's say you do all these and then make your
prediction accuracy to from 1% to 10%, and then
you make say 100 predictions, 10 of them will be
correct, say one of them will be really, really
correct. Meaning it will have an outside impact
that outweighs everything. And I think that is
kind of how many-- I've seen many general thing in
life that you really have to be right a few times.
So why-- so if we think about why predicting
the future is difficult or maybe even think
about the extreme case where we can all
do the prediction with perfect accuracy,
almost perfect accuracy. So here, I'm going to
do a very simple experiment of dropping this pen,
and follow this same three-step process. So we're
going to identify the dominant driving force.
First of all, what are the driving forces
acting on this pen? Gravity downwards,
and is that all? We also have say air friction,
right? If I drop it, and that will cause what's
called a drag force acting upwards. And
actually, depending on how I drop this,
the orientation, the aerodynamic interaction
will be so complicated that we don't currently
have any analytical way of modeling that.
We can do it with the CFD, the computational
fluid dynamics, but it will be non-trivial. So
we can neglect that. This is heavy enough that
gravity is probably the only dominant force, so
we simplify the problem. Second, do we understand
this dominant driving force, which is gravity? And
we do because we have this Newtonian mechanics,
which provides a reasonably good model.
And then with that, we can predict the future
trajectory of this pen. And if we remember
from this dynamics class, if we have this
initial velocity is 0, I'm not going to put any
velocity. And then let's say position is 0 here,
and then 1/2 GT squared will give a precise
trajectory of this pen as I drop this. So
if there is a driving force, single driving
force that we really understand, it's actually
possible to predict what's going to happen.
So then, why do we really fear about predicting
the future in the most general sense? And I argue
that, among many reasons, the number of driving
force, the sheer number of dominant driving forces
acting on the general prediction is so complicated
and their interaction creates a complexity
that we cannot predict the most general sense.
So here is my cartoon way of thinking about the
prediction of future. x-axis, we have a number
of dominant driving forces, y-axis we have
a prediction difficulty. So on the left hand
side, we have a dropping of pen it's a very
simple case. It's a difficulty it's very small,
you just need to learn physics. And then, as
you add more stuff, it just becomes impossible.
So how does this fit into the AI research? And
you might think, OK, I see all the time things
are coming in, we are bombarded by new things,
and some people will come up with the new agent,
new modality, new MMLU score or whatever. We just
see so many things it just I'm not even able to
catch up with the latest thing, how can I even
hope to predict the future of the AI research?
But I argue that it's actually simpler
because there is a dominant driving force
that is governing a lot if any if not all
of the AI research. And because of that,
I would like to point out that, it's actually
closer to the left than to the right than we
actually may perceive. So what is the driving
force? Maybe before that, I would like to caveat
that when I do this kind of talk, I would like
to not focus too much on the technical stuff
which you can probably do better in your own
time, but rather I want to share how I think.
And for that, I want to share how my opinion as
is, and so it will be very strongly opinionated.
And by no means I'm saying this is correct or
not, I just wanted to share my perspective. So
coming back to this driving force for AI, what is
that dominant driving force? And here is a plot
from Rich Sutton. And on the y-axis, we have the
calculations plot if you pay $100, and how much
computing power do you get? And it's in log scale.
And then x-axis, we have a time of more than 100
years. So this is actually more than exponential.
And I don't know any trend that is as strong and
as long lasting as this one. So whenever
I see this kind of thing, I should say,
OK, I should not compete with this. And better, I
should try to leverage as much as possible. And so
what this means is, you get 10x more compute every
five years if you spend the same amount of dollar.
And so in other words, you get the cost of
compute is going down exponentially. And
this associated scaling is really dominating the
AI research, and that is somewhat hard to take,
but that is, I think, really important to think
about. So coming back to this AI research,
how is this exponentially cheaper compute
drive the AI research? Let's think about
the job of the AI researchers. It is to teach
machines how to think in a very general sense.
And one somewhat unfortunately common approach
is, we think about how we teach machine how we
think we think. So meaning, we model how
we think and then try to incorporate that
into some kind of mathematical model and teach
that. And now, the question is, do we understand
how we think at the very low level? I don't
think we do. I have no idea what's going on.
So it's fundamentally flawed in the sense that
we try to model something that we have no idea
about. And what happens if we go with this kind
of approach is that, it poses a structure that
serves as a shortcut in the short term, and so
you can maybe get a paper or something. But then
it becomes a bottleneck when-- because we don't
know how this will limit further scaling up.
More fundamentally what this is doing is,
we are limiting the degree of freedom we
are giving to the machines, and that will
backfire at some point. And this has been
going on for decades. And bitter lesson
is, I think the single most important
piece of writing in AI. And it says, this is my
wording by the way. Say past 70 years of entire
AI research can be summarized into developing
progressively more general method with weaker
modeling assumptions or inductive biases, and add
more data and compute, in other words scale up.
And that has been the recipe of entire AI
research, not fancy things. And if you think
about this, the models of 2000 is a lot more
difficult than what we use now. And so it's much
easier to get into AI nowadays from technical
perspective. So this is, I think, the really
the key information. We have this compute cost is
going down exponentially, and it's getting cheaper
faster than we are becoming a better researcher.
So don't compete with that and just try to
leverage that as much as possible, and that is
the driving force that I wanted to identify.
And I'm not saying this is the only driving
force, but this is the dominant driving force,
so we can probably neglect the other ones. So
here's a graphical version of that. x-axis we have
a compute, y-axis we have a performance of some
kind. Let's think about some general intelligence.
And let's look at two different methods. One,
with more structure, more modeling assumptions,
fancier math, whatever. And then the other one
is a less structure. What you see is typically,
you start with a better performance when you have
a low compute regime, and then but it plateaus
because of some kind of structure backfiring.
And then with the less structure because we give
a lot more freedom to the model, it doesn't work
in the beginning. But then as we add more compute,
it starts working, and then it gets better, we
call this more scalable method. So does that mean
we should just go with the least structure,
most freedom to the model possible way from
the get go? And the answer is, obviously, no.
Let's think about even less structured case. This
red one here is, it will pick up a lot later and
requires a lot more compute. So it really depends
on where we are. We cannot indefinitely wait
for the most general case. And so let's think
about the case where our compute situation is
at this dotted line. If we're here, we should
choose this last structure one as opposed to
this even less structure one because the other
one doesn't really work and the other one works.
But crucially, we need to remember that we are
adding some structure because we don't have
compute, so we need to remove that later. And
so the difference between these two methods is
that additional inductive biases or structure we
impose, somewhat impose that typically don't get
removed. So adding this. What that means is that,
at the given level of compute data algorithmic
development and architecture that we have,
there's like an optimal inductive bias or
structure that we can add to the problem
to make the progress. And that has been
really how we have made so much progress.
But these are like shortcuts that hinder further
scaling later on, so we have to remove them
later on when we have more compute, better
algorithm, or whatever. And as a community,
we do adding structure very well and because
there's an incentive structure with like papers.
You add a nice one then you get a paper. But
removing that doesn't really get you much,
so that we don't really do that. And I
think we should do a lot more of those.
So maybe another implication of this bitter lesson
is that, because of this what is better in the
long-term almost necessarily looks worse now. And
this is quite unique to AI research because the
AI research of current paradigm is learning based
method. Meaning that we are giving models freedom,
the machines choose how they learn.
So because we need to give more freedom, it
gives-- it's a more chaotic at the beginning, so
it doesn't work. But then when it started working,
we can put in more compute and then it can be
better, so it's really important to have this
in mind. So to summarize, we have identified this
dominant driving force behind the AI research,
and that is this exponentially cheaper
compute, and associated scaling up.
Now, that we have identified if you remember
back from my initial slides, we-- the next
step is to understand this driving force better.
And so that we're going to spend most of the time
doing that. And for that, we need to go back
to some history of transformer because this is
a transformers class and analyze key structures
and decisions that were made by the researchers
at the time, and why they did that. Whether
that was an optimal structure that could have
been added at the time, and why they might
be irrelevant now, and should we remove that?
And we'll go through some of the
practices of this. And hopefully,
this will give you some flavor of what
scaling research looks like. So now,
we'll go into a little bit of the technical
stuff, tech transformer architecture,
there are some variants. I'll talk about
three of them. First, is the encoder-decoder,
which is the original transformer,
which has a little bit more structure.
Second one is the encoder-only, which is
popularized by Bert. And then third one
is decoder-only, which you can think of it as a
current like GPT-3 or other language models, this
has a lot less structure than the encoder-decoder.
So these are the three types we'll go into detail.
Second, the encoder-only is actually not that
useful in the most general sense. It still has
some place, but we will just briefly go over
that, and then spend most of the time comparing
1 and 3. So one has more structure, what's the
implication of that and so on? So first of all,
let's think about what a transformer is, just
at a very high level. Or first principles,
what is a transformer? Is a sequence model.
And sequence model is has an input of a
sequence. So sequence can be-- a sequence
of elements can be words, or images,
or whatever. It's a very general concept. In this
particular example I show you with the words,
sentence is a sequence of words. And then
we the first step is to tokenize it because
we have to represent this word in computers
which requires some kind of encoding scheme,
so we just do it with a fixed number of integers,
and then we have now a sequence of integers.
And then the dominant paradigm nowadays is to
represent each sequence element as a vector,
dense vector, because we know how to multiply them
well. And then so we have a sequence of vectors.
And finally, this sequence model will do the
following. We just want to model the interaction
between sequence elements. And we do that by let
them take the dot product of each other. And if
the dot product is high, we can say semantically
they are more related than the dot products that
is low, and that's kind of the sequence model.
And the transformer is a particular type of
sequence model that uses what's called attention
to model this interaction . So let's get into the
details of this encoder-decoder, which was
the original transformer. It's quite many,
many pieces. So let's go into a little bit a piece
at a time. So starting with the encoder. So here
I'm going to show you an example of machine
translation, which used to be very cool thing.
And so you are-- you have an English sentence that
is good, and then we're going to translate it into
German. So first thing is to encode this into a
dense vector. So here I'm representing it with
this a vector of size three or something.
And then we have to let them take the dot
product. So this lines represent which element
can talk to which element, other elements.
And here because it's an input, we take what is
called a bidirectional attention, so any token
can talk to any other token. And then we have
this MLP or feedforward layer which is per token,
it doesn't have any interaction, we just do
some multiplication just because we can do
it. And then that's one layer, and we repeat that
n times, and that's just the transformer encoder.
And at the end, what you get is the sequence of
vectors each representing the sequence element
in this case a word. So that's the output of this
encoder. Now, let's look at the decoder, which is
similarly shaped stack of layers. So here we put
in as an input what the answer should be. So here,
BOS, is the beginning of sequence, and then das
ist gut, I don't know how to pronounce it, but
that's the German translation of, that is good.
And so we kind of go through the similar process.
Here we have a causal self-attention,
meaning that the tokens of time step t can
only attend to t and before because when we start
generating it, we don't have the future tokens,
so we cannot-- when we train it, we should limit
that, and that way, this is done by like masking,
but this is different from the encoder.
So after this, you can get-- after again,
n layers, you get this sequence output, and you
have this-- the output of sequence, to sequence,
to sequence mapping, this is a general
encoder-decoder architecture. And when you
get this end of sequence, you stop generating
it. So this is the overall picture. Now,
I'll point out some important attention patterns.
So we are translating into German what is into
input to the encoder. So there has to be
some connection between the decoder and
the encoder that is done by this cross
attention mechanism shown in this red,
which is just that each vector representation of
each sequence in the output decoder should attend
to some of them in the encoder, and that is done.
In particular the design feature which is
interesting is that all the layers in the
decoder attend to the final layer output of the
encoder, and we'll come back to the implication
of this design. So yeah, that's that. And now,
move on to the second type of architecture, which
is encoder-only. We'll spend a little bit of time
here. So again, we have to-- we have the same
input, and we go through a similar structure.
And then in this case, the final output is
a single vector. Regardless of the length
of the sequence, we just get a single vector.
And that is that represent the input sequence,
that's a dense vector representation. And then
let's say we do some kind of a sentiment analysis,
we run through a task specific linear
layer to map it to classification
label positive or negative probabilities here.
And that's required for all these task specific
cases. And this is kind of popularized
by Bert. And what this means is that,
here at the time, 2018, when Bert came out
we had the benchmark called glue, which was
a language understanding task. You have a sequence
in classification labels out for most cases. This
was how the field really advanced at the time.
So when we care about such tasks, then there's an
incentive to think about simplifying the problem,
adding the structure to the problem so that we can
make a progress. So this, the additional structure
that was put into this particular architecture is
that we're going to give up on the generation.
If we do that, it becomes a lot simpler problem.
Instead of sequence to sequence, we're talking
about sequence to classification labels,
and that's just so much easier.
And so at some point, 2018, 2019,
a lot of the papers are just research was like,
we sometimes call it Bert engineers, a little
bit change of something get like 0.5% better on
glue, and you get a paper, and things like that.
It was very chaotic error, and-- but if we look at
from this perspective, we are putting the sequence
structure of not generating the sequence that puts
a lot of performance win, but in the long term,
it's not really useful. So we're not going to look
at this encoder-only architecture going forward.
Third architecture, decoder-only. This one is
my favorite personally. And it looks kind of
daunting because of this attention pattern,
but it actually is very simple. So here,
we only have a single stack, and it can actually
generate stuff. And so there's misconception that
some people think this decoder-only architecture
is used for language modeling next to prediction,
so it cannot be used for supervised
learning. But here, we can actually do it.
The trick is to have this input that is good,
concatenate it with the target. And if you do
that, then it just becomes simple to sequence in
sequence out. So what we do is, the self-attention
mechanism here is actually handling both the
cross attention between target and the input,
and self-attention sequence learning within
each. So that's the causal attention.
And then as I mentioned, the output is a
sequence, and then the key design features
are self-attention is serving both roles, and
we are in some sense sharing the parameters
between input and target. So same set of
parameters are applied to both input and
the target sequences. So this is the decoder
only, now, we will go into the comparison.
So I think there are many-- like they look
very different, at least, on the schematics.
So how different are they actually? And I argue
that they're actually quite similar. And so to
illustrate that we're going to transform
starting from this encoder-decoder which
has more structures built in, and then
into the decoder-only architecture and
see what are some of the differences. And then
interpret those differences, those additional
structures, are they relevant nowadays now that
we have more compute better algorithm and so on?
So let's have this table, four differences we'll
see each of them. And then as we go through,
we will populate this table. So let's first
look at this additional cross-attention. What
that means is that, this on the left is an
encoder-decoder, which has this additional
red block, the cross-attention compared
to the simpler one that doesn't have that.
So we want to make it, make the left closer to the
right, so that means we need to either get rid of
it or something. And attention mechanism
has kind of the four projection matrices,
and so self-attention and cross attention
actually have the same number of parameters,
same shape, so we can just share them. So
that's the first step, share both of these,
and then it becomes mostly the same mechanism.
And then so that's the first difference separate
cross-attention or self-attention serving both
roles. Second difference is the parameter sharing.
So what that means is that, between the input and
the target, encoder-decoder architecture uses a
separate parameters. And decoder-only only has
a single stack so it uses the shared parameter.
So if we want to make the left close to right, we
want to share the encoder parameters, so let's do
that. I just color this, so now, they share the
parameters. Third difference is the target to
input attention pattern. So we need to connect the
target to the input. And how does that-- how is it
done? In the encoder-decoder case, we had this
cross attention. And then in the decoder-only,
it's a per the self-attention doing everything.
What the difference is that we have this every
layer of the decoder attending to the final layer
output of the encoder, whereas if you think about
this decoder is actually per layer, within
layer when we are decoding the say word thus,
we are looking at the same layer representation
of the encoder, and that's within layer,
and I think this is the design feature. So if
we want to make this close to that, we have
to bring back this attention to each layer.
So now, layer 1 will be attending to layer
1 of this. And that's then finally, the
last difference is the input attention.
I mentioned about this bidirectional attention.
And because we have this decoder only typically,
with the unidirectional attention, we need to make
them matching, so that's the we can just get rid
of it. I just got rid of the some of the arrows.
So then at this point, these two architectures
are almost identical. A little bit
of difference in the cross attention,
but same number of parameters. And if you have
in deep learning, if you just train these, these
two architecture in the same task, same data, I
think, you will get pretty much within the noise,
probably closer than if you train the same
thing twice. So I would say they are identical.
And so these are the main differences. Now,
we'll look at what are the additional structures,
what they mean, it means. So yeah.
That's the populated table now,
and then so we can say that encoder-decoder
compared to the decoder-only architecture has
these additional structures inductive biases
built in, so let's go into each of them.
The first one is what encoder-decoder tries added
as a structure is that, input and the target
sequences are sufficiently different that we--
it will be useful to use a separate parameters,
that's the assumption. And so why is that a
useful? When can that assumption be useful?
And one example is machine translation. Back
when the transformer was introduced in 2017,
translation was really popular task, and
it was difficult, considered difficult.
And because it's a sequence-to-sequence and
you can actually have a blue score which is
heuristic based method that can give you a single
number and then people can optimize that. So what
that in that task, we have this input and
target in completely different languages. So
if the goal is to learn translation only,
then it kind of makes sense to have, OK,
this parameter in the encoder will take care of
the English, and this parameter in the decoder
will take care of the German, that seems natural.
And what about now? Modern language models is
about learning knowledge. And it's not just
about translation or not even about language,
languages comes up as a byproduct of doing
this next token prediction and translation as
well. So does it make sense to have a separate
parameter for this kind of situation now? We
have some knowledge in German, some knowledge in
English, and we-- if anything we want to combine
them. And if we represent them in a separate
parameters, I don't think that's natural.
So I would say with this much more general,
larger models that can do a lot of things,
this assumption seems very unnatural to me. Second
example is a little bit more modern. Two years ago
when I was at Google and with Jason, we did this
instruction fine tuning work. And what this is,
is you take the pre-trained model, and then just
fine tune on academic data set, and so that it
can understand the natural language instruction.
So the detail doesn't matter, but here let's think
about the performance gain by doing this fine
tuning on two different architectures we tried. So
first five is the Flan-T5, which is T5 base which
is the encoder-decoder architecture. Last one,
the latter five decoder-only architecture based
on PaLM. So we spent 99% of the time on PaLM,
optimizing a lot of these, and then at the
end we just spent like three days on T5.
But the performance gain was a lot higher on
this. And I was really confused about this,
and in a very good way. And after the paper
was published, I wanted to take a little bit
deeper into why this might be the case. So my
hypothesis is that, it's about the length. So
academic data sets we use, we use like 1,832
tasks. And here they have this very distinctive
characteristic where we have a long input,
long in order to make the task more difficult.
But then we cannot make the target long
because if we do, there's no way to create it,
so there's fundamental challenge of that. So
what happens is, you have a long text of input
and then short text of the target. And so this
is kind of the length distribution of what it
went into the Flan fine tuning. So then you
see this, you have a very different sequence
going into the encoder as an input, and the very
different type of sequence going into the target.
So now, this encoder-decoder architecture has
an assumption that they will be very different.
That structure really shines because of this.
It was a kind of an accident, but that was,
I think, why this really architecture was just
suitable for fine tuning with the academic data
sets. What about now? Do we care about this
kind of assumption? And if you think about the
general use cases of language models nowadays,
if anything the more interesting cases involve
longer generation, longer target.
Just because we cannot grade them,
doesn't mean that we are not interested in them.
Actually, if anything we are more interested
in that. So now we have this longer target
situation, so this separate sequence length
parameter doesn't seem to make much sense. And
moreover, we think about this chat application
like ChatGPT, we do multi-turn conversation.
And then so what is a target of this turn
becomes the input of the next turn. And then
my question is, does that make sense to even
think about a different parameters if next turn
is going to be the same thing? So that was the
first inductive bias we just mentioned. And then
the second structure is that, target element can
only attend to the fully encoded ones, the
final output of the encoder. Let's look at
this additional structure, what that means.
So as I mentioned, we have this very top
layer attending to it. And so in deep neural nets,
typically, we see that the bottom layers and the
top layers encode information at a very different
level. Meaning that, for example, in computer
vision, lower layer-- the bottom layers encode
something like edges, top layers, higher levels
combining the features, something like cat face.
And so we call this deep learning a hierarchical
representation learning method. And so now the
question is, if decoder layer one attends to
encoder final layer, which probably has
a very different level of information,
is that some kind of an information bottleneck
which actually motivated the original attention
mechanism? And in practice I would say in my
experience doesn't really make any difference,
and that's because my experience was limited
to say 25, 24 layers of encoder of T5.
So layer one attended to 24, probably fine. But
what if we have 10x or 1,000x more layers, would
that be problematic? I'm not really comfortable
with that. So I think this is also unnecessary
design that maybe we need to revisit. Final
structure we're going to talk about is the,
when we do this, there's a bi-directional thing
in the encoder-decoder. Let's think about that.
So yeah. Bi-directional input attention, is
that really necessary? So when we had this Bert,
B in Bert stands for bi-directional. 2018 when
we were solving like question answering squad,
actually it was very difficult task. So if you
have any additional trick, it can make a huge
difference. Bidirectionality was really useful,
I think, maybe boosting up the squad score by
like 20, so it was really huge thing. But at
scale, I don't think this matters that much.
This is my highly anecdotal experience, so we
did in Flan-2, we tried both bi-directional and
uni-directional fine tuning, didn't really make
much difference. So but I want to point out this
bidirectionality, actually bring in an engineering
challenge for modern multi-turn chat application.
So at every turn, the new input has to be encoded.
Again, and for uni-directional attention it's
much, much better, so here is what I mean by
that. So let's think about this more modern
conversation between user and assistant,
how are you? Bad, and why? And so here,
if we think about the bi-directional case, we
will-- and when we generate bad, we need to encode
this input with the bi-directional thing, which
is fine. And then after the bad is generated,
when we're trying to generate why, we'll need to
encode how, again, because how can attend to bad,
so we need to do everything from scratch again.
In contrast, if we do uni-directional one,
we can do much, much better because now when we
are trying to generate why, we don't have to redo
how because we cannot attend to the future tokens,
so we don't have to do anything. So if you see the
difference, this part can be cached and then this
part is the only thing that can has to be encoded
again. So this kind of makes a big difference
when we think about multiple turns going on.
So I would say, bi-directional attention, that
well, in 2018, which is mostly sold by scale,
and now because of this engineering challenge,
we don't really need that. So to conclude,
we have looked into this driving force,
dominant driving force covering this research,
and that was this exponentially cheaper
compute and associated scaling effort.
And so to understand this driving force, we
analyzed some of the additional structures
added to the encoder-decoder compared to the
decoder only, and then thought about how--
what that means as a from the perspective of
scaling. And I wanted to just conclude with
this remark. So we have looked at these kind
of analysis, which are all-- one can say, this
is just historical artifacts and doesn't matter.
But if you do many of these, now you look at the
current events. You can hopefully think about
those in a more unified manner and then see,
OK, what assumptions in my problem that I need
to revisit? And are they relevant? And if not,
why? And you have an answer to it. Is can we
do it with a more general thing and scale up?
And so I hope you can go back and really
think about these problems. And together
we can really shape the future of AI in
a really nice way, so that's it. Thanks.